Alexander Velichkin

Voronezh +7 (915) 582-9542 2dolby@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a .Net developer with 8+ years of experience in creating web and desktop applications and small team leadership. I have developed web, desktop, and mobile apps and devoted a lot of time improving the performance of existing applications. I specialize in .NET technologies and also work with MS SQL and PostgreSQL. Interested in .Net Core and DevOps practices.

Employment History

Debate.org (via Toptal)

April 2018 - Present

Senior C# .Net Developer

- 1. Created a service that performs background jobs and communicates with the web application via RabbitMQ. Added a Regex-based background job that automatically filters user content and removes spam.
- 2. Integrated third-party services with a web application (Google ReCaptcha, Google Analytics, Google Adsense, Taboola Ads, Pingdom, SendGrid).
- 3. Improved performance of a web application running classic ASP, WebForms, DevExpress, jQuery, and MS SOL.
- 4. Developed a tool for admins to create their own pages using DevExpress HTML editor.
- 5. Set up a developer and test environment for existing web applications using AWS. Set up a CI/CD process using Azure DevOps.
- 6. Maintained Windows Servers (web apps and background services) and AWS RDS (MS SQL Server) machines.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET Web Forms, DevExpress, Entity Framework 6, MS SQL Server, Classic ASP, jQuery, RabbitMQ, Git, Azure DevOps

Donation Kiosk (via Toptal)

August 2017 - October 2017

Senior WPF/C# Developer

- 1. Developed a WPF application for touchscreens.
- 2. Customized WPF controls (Buttons, Labels, ListViews, Popup windows) based on client's mockups.
- 3. Added data download from client's PHP back-end via JSON and storing it locally with auto-updating.
- 4. Added an auto-updating functionality for a desktop application.

Technologies: WPF, GIT, XAML, JSON

Atos It Solutions and Services LLC

May 2016 - May 2018

Senior C# .Net Developer & Developer & Senior C# .Net Developer & Developer &

Developer

- 1. Developed a web application using ASP.NET Web Forms and DevExpress components.
- 2. Built modules for Excel reporting using ComponentPro.
- 3. Developed a Windows service to perform background long-processing operations.
- 4. Created Xamarin. Forms application UI components.
- 5. Developed a stand-alone library, that is used by both Xamarin. Forms and ASP.NET MVC projects and used

to perform their communication (serialization, encryption, validation, etc).

- 6. Built an Excel reporting module that is used by WPF application and ASP.NET MVC application.
- 7. Created a library to synchronize MS SQL Server database and local MySQL database to let users work in WPF application locally with MySQL database and auto synchronization with MS SQL Server.

Technologies: MS SQL Server 2012, C#, ASP.NET Web Forms, ADO.NET, DevExpress, ComponentPro, EVO PDF Toolkit, Xamarin.Forms, Prism, MVVM, GIT, TFS

MotionGlass (Startup)

February 2016 - March 2017

Senior C# .NET Developer

- 1. Developed a desktop WPF application using Intel RealSense camera (before Kinect 2).
- 2. Built a web-based admin panel using ASP.NET MVC and MS SQL Server.
- 3. Created a WCF Service for interaction between a WPF application and a web-based admin panel.

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, WPF, WCF, Kinect 2, Intel RealSense, MS SQL Server, Entity Framework 6, GIT

Home Credit and Finance Bank LLC

February 2016 - May 2016

Load Testing Engineer

- 1. Developed test plans for load-testing using JMeter.
- 2. Developed scripts with Python 3 to analyze log files.
- 3. Prepared sample data for test plans using the Oracle database.

Technologies: JMeter, Python 3

BI-Leasing LLC

August 2012 - February 2016

ActionScript 3 Developer | C# .NET Developer

- 1. Worked as a .NET architect and senior developer in the development of an internal application for a local insurance company using PostgreSQL, ASP.Net Web API, AngularJS, and FastReport .Net.
- 2. Developed an advertisement application using Kinect 2, WPF, and ASP.NET MVC.
- 3. Built an internet kiosk application with WPF.
- 4. Created a cartographic application using the OpenStreetMap API and ActionScript 3.0 for Windows, Android, and iOS platforms.
- 5. Developed stand-alone library of ActionScript 3 UI components, that were used by several teams in different projects.

Technologies: C# .NET, WPF, Web API, LINQ, AngularJS, FastReport .Net, Entity Framework 6, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, ActionScript 3, GIT, SVN, Visual Studio, Kinect 2

Top Skills

C#	****
ASP.NET	****
JavaScript	****
CSS	****
.NET Core	****
Azure DevOps	****
RabbitMQ	****
MS SQL Server	****
PostgreSQL	****
GIT	****
TFS	****



Languages

Russian $\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar$ English $\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar$

Education

Voronezh State Technical University

Master degree in Information Systems and Technologies

Voronezh State Technical University

Bachelor degree in Information Systems and Technologies

Voronezh, Voronezh Oblast Graduated June 2013

Voronezh, Voronezh Oblast Graduated June 2011

Certifications

Microsoft Certified Professional

• https://mcp.microsoft.com/Anonymous/Transcript/Validate

Transcript ID: 1210025 Access Code: 112324674

Xamarin Certified Mobile Professional

• https://university.xamarin.com/certification?q=alexander.velichkin@atos.net#verify